Guide to the National Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Conferences, Series IX
  - Other Conferences
    - Interfaith Consultation on Religion and Race, NY,NY:Minutes The Student Leadership Conference on Race and Religion, Washington, D.C.: Correspondence, mailing list, memos, 1963 (Box 54, Folder 746)
    - NSCF Sponsored Ecumenical Regional Conferences: Promotional materials and reports, 1963-1965 (Box 54, Folder 747)
    - National of Council of Churches Sixth World Order Study Conference, St. Louis, Missouri: Addresses given at conference, October 1965 (Box 54, Folder 748)
    - NSCF Africa Conference: Conference planning memos and minutes and promotional materials, 1965-1966 (Box 55, Folder 749)
    - WSCF Teaching Conference, Strasbourg, France: Conference materials, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 750)
    - Delegate biography sheets to an unknown conference (Box 55, Folder 751)
- Publications and Printed Materials, Series X
  The Publications and Printed Materials series is comprised of three subseries: National Student Christian Federation Publications, World Student Christian Federation Publications, and Publications from Other Organizations. All materials arranged alphabetically by format.
  - National Student Christian Federation Publications
    - Book: Fifty Years of Faith and Order: an Interpretation of hte Faith and Order Movement by John E. Skoglund and J. Robert Nelson, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 752)
    - Brochures and flyers (Box 55, Folder 753)
    - Circular documents I-2 through I-41, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 754)
    - Circular documents I-43 through I-79, 1959-1960 (Box 55, Folder 755)
    - Circular documents I-80 through I-220, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 756)
    - Circular documents II-4 through II-77, 1960-1961 (Box 55, Folder 757)
    - Circular documents II-78 through II-145, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 758)
    - Circular documents II-145 through II-203, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 759)
    - Circular documents III-1 through III-65, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 760)
    - Circular documents III-66 through III-113, 1961 (Box 56, Folder 761)
    - Circular documents III-114 through III-170, 1961-1962 (Box 56, Folder 762)
    - Circular documents III-171 through III-272, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 763)
    - Circular documents III-273 through III-318, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 764)
    - Circular documents IV-5 through IV-87 (incomplete), 1962-1963 (Box 57, Folder 765)
    - Circular documents IV-66 through IV-135, 1962-1963 (Box 57, Folder 766)
    - Circular documents IV-138 through IV-279, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 767)
    - Circular documents IV-279 through IV-284, 1963 (Box 57, Folder 768)
    - Circular documents V-12 through V-94, 140 (incomplete), 1963-1964 (Box 57, Folder 769)
    - Circular documents VII-3 through 4, VII-11 through 40 (incomplete), 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 770)
    - Circular documents VII-65 through VII-88 (incomplete), 1966 (Box 57, Folder 771)
    - Circular documents VII-90 through VII-106 (incomplete), 1966 (Box 57, Folder 772)
    - Circular documents: unnumbered reports from CWM, 1966 (Box 57, Folder 773)
    - Directories and Committee membership lists, 1965-1966 (Box 57, Folder 774)
    - Manual: Resource and Reflection: Concerning the Christian Ministry Among Students from Other Committees. Includes USCC manual., 1957, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 775)
    - Manual: Resource and Reflection Concerning the Christian Ministry Among Students fro Other Countries. Includes memos and sales figures for publication, 1961-1962 (Box 58, Folder 776)
    - Newsletter: Communique, 1959-1963 (Box 58, Folder 777)
    - Newsletter: Communique, 1963-1966 (Box 58, Folder 778)
    - Newsletter: In the Midst of Strife: NSCF Civil Rights Newsletter issue no. 2, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 779)
    - Newsletter: NSCF-CCWAIS International Campus News, 1965, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 780)
    - Newsletter: The Second Look: Analyzing World Issues of Interest to Students (A Biweekly Feature Service of the CWM), 1965, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 781)
    - Newsletter: SVM Newsletter, 1959-1961 (Box 59, Folder 781a)
    - Newsletter: NSCF WSCF Newsletter, 1964 (Box 59, Folder 782)
    - Serial and Occasional Paper: The Interseminarian and Forms and Varieties of Christian Worship by Massey H. Shepherd, Jr., 1962-1963 (Box 59, Folder 782a)
  - World Student Christian Federation Publications
    - Books: Includes A New University for a New World by Jean Jousselin, 1950, 1954, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 783)
    - Brochure in German re. WSCF, undated (Box 60, Folder 784)
    - Circular letters re. Life and Mission of the Church project, 1958-1963 (Box 60, Folder 785)
    - Circular letters, miscellaneous, 1960-1963 (Box 60, Folder 786)
    - Directory, 1962-1963 (Box 60, Folder 787)
    - Minutes: European Council, 1955-1956 (Box 60, Folder 788)
    - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1954, 1958 (Box 60, Folder 789)
    - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1959, 1961 (Box 60, Folder 790)
    - Minutes: Executive Committee, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 791)
    - Minutes: General Committee, 1960 (Box 60, Folder 792)
    - Minutes and Reports: General Committee, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 793)
    - Minutes and Reports: General Committee, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 794)
    - Minutes: Officer's Meeting, 1953-1954 (Box 61, Folder 795)
    - Minutes: Officer's Meeting, 1955-1956 (Box 61, Folder 796)
    - Minutes: Officer's Meeting, 1957, 1960, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 797)
    - Newsletter: The Life and Mission of the Church Bulletin, 1958-1960 (Box 61, Folder 798)
    - Newsletter: The Life and Mission of the Church Bulletin, 1960-1964 (Box 61, Folder 799)
    - Newsletter: Schools Newsletter: Occasional for the Staff of High School Movements. Issued by the World's Student Christian Federation, 1957-1960 (Box 61, Folder 800)
    - Pamphlets: The Christian Community in the Academic World, Foreign Students: a New Ministry in a New World, and WSCF, 1963, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 801)
    - Reports re. Africa including Leadership Training Course for Central Africa, South Africa, East Africa, and Madagascar, 1960-1961 (Box 62, Folder 802)
    - Reports: General Committee, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 803)
    - Reports: General Committee, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 804)
    - Reports: Includes The Relationships of the World's Student Christian Federation and Student Christian Movements with the International Fellowship of Evangelical Students and Intervarsity Fellowships, 1957, 1960, 1961 (Box 62, Folder 805)
    - Reports: WSCF Teaching Conference, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 806)
    - Reports: Teaching Conference, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 807)
    - Serial: Federation News, 1960, 1961, 1965 (Box 63, Folder 808)
    - Study Guide: West African Study Project Study Outlines 1-8, undated (Box 62, Folder 809)
    - The Task of the Christian University: an Essay by John Coleman, 1946 (Box 63, Folder 810)
    - Working Papers for General Committee, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 811)
  - Publications from Other Organizations
    - Book: The History of the U.S. National Student Association Relations with the International Union of Students by Peter T. Jones and The Role of Christian Colleges in India Today by J.W. Airan, 1956, 1961 (Box 64, Folder 812)
    - Booklets: Student Christian Movement in India, 1958, 1962 (Box 64, Folder 813)
    - Brochures: Includes brochures from Church World Service, Ecumenical Ministries, and YMCA, circa 1960's (Box 64, Folder 814)
    - Journal: Concern, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 815)
    - Manual: Religion in Life Week: a Guide by James L. Stoner and United States National Student Association Handbook, 1956, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 816)
    - Newsletters: National Council of Churches newsletters including Information Service, The Religious Newsweekly, and NEWS, 1961, 1964, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 817)
    - Newsletter: Protestant Churches in Czechoslovakia, 1961, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 818)
    - Newsletters: Miscellaneous from Student Christian Movements in Colombia, Germany, and South Africa., 1960, 1963 (Box 64, Folder 819)
    - Newsletter: YCS Bulletin, 1966 (Box 64, Folder 820)
    - Newsletters and Journals: International Union of Students newsletters including Information Bulletin, News Service, and World Student News, 1953, 1960-1962 (Box 64, Folder 821)
    - Pamphlets from International Union of Students including 16 Questions and Answers about the IUS ,and Korea and Its Students, 1959, 1961, 1962, and undated (Box 64, Folder 822)
    - Paper: "United Ministries in Higher Education: a Policy Paper", 1965 (Box 64, Folder 823)
    - Reports: Academic Programs Abroad: an Exploration of Their Assets and Liabilities, Foreign Study for U.S. Undergraduates: a Survey of College Programs and Policies, and Transplanted Students: a Report of the National Conference on Undergraduate Study Abroad, 1958, 1960 (Box 65, Folder 824)
    - Reports from International Union of Students: Conference Reports including IUS-FEU International Seminar on Illiteracy, 1960, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 825)
    - Reports from University Christian Mission of NCCC: Project Reports, 1956, 1960 (Box 65, Folder 826)
    - Reports from World University Service including Programme of Action: 1966, 1966, undated (Box 65, Folder 827)
    - Workbook from the National Student Council of the YMCA's Annual Meeting, 1966 (Box 65, Folder 828)
- Members and Related Organizations of the NSCF, Series XI
  The Members and Related Organization series is divided into two subseries: Member Organizations and Related Organizations. Materials organized alphabetically by organization name.
  - Member Organizations
    - Methodist Student Movement: Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 65, Folder 829)
    - Methodist Movement: Papers from National Conference and Regional Conferences, 1961-1964 (Box 65, Folder 830)
    - United Campus Christian Fellowship: Articles of Operation and papers re. UCCF merger, 1959 (Box 65, Folder 831)
    - United Campus Christian Fellowship: Minutes, 1964 (Box 65, Folder 832)
    - United Christian Campus Fellowship: United Ministries in Higher Education minutes, May 10-14, 1965 (Box 65, Folder 833)
  - Related Organizations
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A.: Association of Council Secretaries, 1959 (Box 65, Folder 834)
    - NCCC: By Laws and Constitution includes revisions, 1957-1965 (Box 65, Folder 835)
    - NCCC: Commission on Higher Education memos and minutes, 1962-1963 (Box 66, Folder 836)
    - NCCC: Commission on Missionary Education reports, 1960, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 837)
    - NCCC: Commission on Order and Organization minutes, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 838)
    - NCCC: Consultation on Christian Laymen Overseas, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 839)
    - NCCC: Consultation on Christian Laymen Overseas, 1960 (Box 66, Folder 840)
    - NCCC: Consultation on Missionary Concerns, February 5-7, 1963 (Box 66, Folder 841)
    - NCCC: Consultation on Short Term Service, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 842)
    - NCCC: Department of Campus Christian Life papers and reports, 1964-1965 (Box 66, Folder 843)
    - NCCC: Division of Christian Education, Committee on Youth Work minutes, 1951-1952 (Box 66, Folder 844)
    - NCCC: Division of Christian Education, Committee on Youth Work memo, minutes, and report, 1953-1956, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 845)
    - NCCC: Division of Home Missions reports, 1959-1961 (Box 66, Folder 846)
    - NCCC: Division of Christian Ministries directory, meeting agenda, calendar, etc., 1965 (Box 66, Folder 847)
    - NCCC: Ecumenical Education reports, 1956 (Box 66, Folder 848)
    - NCCC: General Board minutes, 1962, 1964 (Box 66, Folder 849)
    - NCCC: Joint Department Christian Vocation by laws, memos, statement of purpose, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 850)
    - NCCC: Pronouncements issued, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 851)
    - NCCC: Reports includes annual report and Report on Internal Structure and Administrative Organization of the National Council of the Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., 1963, 1963, 1964, 1966 (Box 67, Folder 852)
    - NCCC: Resolutions, 1961, 1964 (Box 67, Folder 853)
    - NCCC: Staff Liaison Committee on International Affairs memos and minutes, 1959-1960 (Box 67, Folder 854)
    - NCCC: United Church Men Between US newsletter, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 855)
    - Young Friends of North America: Relationship to NSCF, 1962 (Box 67, Folder 856)
    - YMCA/YWCA: Correspondence and reports re. relationship to the NSCF, 1961 (Box 67, Folder 857)
    - YMCA/YWCA: Minutes of the Estes Conference, June 6-12, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 858)
    - YMCA/YWCA: Workbooks for annual meeting, August 28-September 4, 1962 (Box 67, Folder 859)
    - YMCA/YWCA: Workbook for annual meeting, August 27-September 4, 1963 (Box 67, Folder 860)